Register of the Latin American Subject Collection, 1932-2000
Hoover Institution Archives
Latin American Subject Collection,
1932-2000
XX744
5 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 cubic foot box, 1 videotape cassette, 12 phonorecords. (4.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, correspondence, position papers, bulletins, serial issues, newsletters, campaign material, speeches, minutes, resolutions, printed matter, and audiovisual materials, relating to political conditions in various Latin American countries, especially to guerrilla activities, election campaigns and civil rights; and to United States foreign policy in Latin America.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Latin America.; Latin America--History--20th century.; Central America--History--1951-; Elections--Central America.; Central America; Civil rights--Central America.; United States--Foreign relations--Latin America.; Latin America--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations.; Phonorecords.; Video tapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1994 (Boxes 1-3, 5-6)
  Reports, correspondence, position papers, bulletins, serial issues, newsletters, flyers, campaign material, circulars, speeches, clippings, minutes, resolutions, charts, photographs, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1936-1991 (Box 4)
  Election material, serial issues, flyers, religious instructional material, prints, political poems, fables and stories by Roque Dalton, Jorge Luis Oviedo, and Roberto Sosa
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, ca. 1963-1987 (Record cabinet, Tape cabinet)
  12 phonorecords of songs and speeches from various Latin American and Central American countries, ca. 1963-1981, and 1 videotape cassette entitled Minefield, relating to Uruguay, Chile and Argentina, 1987
CONTAINER LIST
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1994
  - General
    - General (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
      - Newsletter, bulletin, speeches, pamphlets, serial issue, printed article, reports, and a flyer, 1969-1989. Primarily material published in the United States
      - Reports, pamphlets, speeches and other printed matter in English, 1966-1993, concerning political and economic conditions in Latin America and United States foreign policy in Latin America. Includes material on United States military interventions in Latin America, business investments, narcotics traffic and Latin American immigration to the United States (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Carter Center. Pamphlets, statements by Jimmy Carter, press releases, clippings, reports, and newsletters, 1988-1990. Primarily relates to electoral observations in Haiti, Guyana, Nicaragua, and the Dominican Republic (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sanchez, Nestor D.. Interview with and speeches by Nestor D. Sanchez, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Inter-American Affairs, 1981-1986, concerning security issues involving the United States and Latin America (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Central America. Newsletters, position papers, speech, leaflets, clippings, pamphlets, serial issue, and reports, 1983-1993. Includes material relating to human rights, regional leftist organizations, and peace plans (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Dominican Republic. Speech, pamphlets, program statement, serial issues, report and miscellany, 1965-1994. Includes material published by the Partido Comunista Dominicano (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Ecuador. Report, printed excerpt, and program statement by the Partido Comunista del Ecuador, 1974-1987, and two pamphlets of the Instituto Ecuatoriano de Economia Politica, 1993 (Folder 3-4)
  - Grenada. Reports, speech transcript, and newsletters, 1983-1989. Includes material relating to the death of Maurice Bishop. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 5)
  - Guyana. Pamphlet issued by the People's Progressive Party, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - Haiti. Pamphlets, and reports on 1990 elections, 1980-1992 (Folder 7)
  - Jamaica. Report on 1989 election, 1989 (Folder 8)
  - Martinique. Serial issue (Parti Communiste Martiniquais), 1963 (Folder 9)
  - Paraguay. News bulletins, report on 1989 election, and pamphets, 1932-1989. Includes material relating to the Chaco War with Bolivia (Folder 10-11)
  - Puerto Rico. Leaflet, pamphlet, and report, 1979-1988 (Folder 12-13)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1936-1991.
  - Election material, serial issues, flyers, religious instructional material, prints, political poems, printed fables and stories by Roque Dalton, Jorge Luis Oviedo, and Roberto Sosa. (Box 4)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, ca. 1963-1987
  - Phonorecords of songs and speeches from various Latin American and Central American countries, ca. 1963-1981
    - "Alliance for Progress." Six records of speeches by Milton S. Eisenhower, Raul Prebisch, Jose Figueres, Teodoro Moscoso and Dean Rusk about the Alliance for Progress (Phonorecord-cabinet Phonorecord cabinet, Folder 1-6)
    - "Cancion Protesta: Protest Song of Latin America." One record of songs by various artists, 1970 (Folder 7)
    - "Dominican Republic: La Hora Esta LLegando! The Time Is Coming!" One record of songs by Expresion Joven, 1974 (Folder 8)
    - "Ecuador: The Cry of Freedom! El Grito de Libertad!" One record of songs by Jatari, 1976 (Folder 9)
    - "Como El Filo del Machete, Like the Edge of the Machete." One record of Puerto Rican songs by Andre Jimenez, 1978 (Folder 10)
    - "Tengo Puerto Rico en Mi Corazon, I Have Puerto Rico in My Heart." One record of songs by Pepe y Flora, 1971 (Folder 11)
    - "Viva Puerto Rico Libre." One record of songs by various artists, 1978 (Folder 12)
  - 1 videotape cassette entitled Minefield, relating to Uruguay, Chile, and Argentina, 1987 (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)